Dr Noor Ul An Bandey

noorulanbandey@gmail.com Jammu, J&K, +91-9596626581 LinkedIn

Summary

I'm an MBBS graduate with one year of working experience in the Medical ICU. I'd describe myself as a hardworking, self-driven and disciplined. I've always had a strong passion for medicine and learning the human body. Becoming a doctor has allowed me to use my passion to help the society. Aside from my studies, I thoroughly enjoy trekking, adventurous outside sports and reading books.

Education

Acharya Shri Chander College of Medical Sciences and Hospital (ASCOMS) MBBS (Bachelor of Medicine, Bachelor of Surgery)

Jammu, JK August 2022

Skills

Clinical Practices, Research Skills, Public Health, Data Collection, Communication, Organization Skills

Experience

Government Medical College & AH

Junior Resident

Rajouri, India

Sept 2023 - Sept 2024

- Efficiently manage patients in both the ICU and ward settings
- Regularly coordinate with multidisciplinary team, consult with senior colleagues to ensure optimal treatment plans and outcomes
- Conduct thorough patient assessments, perform complex procedures and interpret diagnostic tests.

Acharya Shri Chander College of Medical Sciences and Hospital

Medical Intern

Jammu, India

Aug 2022 - Aug 2023

- Clinical skills and patient care which involved history taking and examination along with diagnostic and treatment planning.
- Gain hands-on experience with essential procedure like IV catheterization, suturing and biopsies as well as understanding their roles in diagnosis and treatment.
- Develop strong communication skills for better patient interaction and interdisciplinary approach for patient management.

Indian Red Cross Society (IRCS)

Student Volunteer

Jammu, India

May 2022 - Aug 2023

- Assisted in organizing blood donation drives and health camps, contributing to community health initiatives.
- Provided first aid and basic medical care during emergencies and events, enhancing public safety.
- Engaged in health awareness campaigns, educating the public on topics like hygiene, vaccination, and disease prevention.

Publications

Bilateral Giant subcostal lipoma-A case report

Dec 2022

- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team to analyze and document the clinical presentation and treatment of a rare giant lipoma
- Conducted a comprehensive review of literature to support the case findings and contribute to medical knowledge on lipoma treatment and recurrence prevention.
- Published the research in the International Journal of Medical Sciences and Advanced Clinical Research, enhancing the understanding of surgical interventions for benign tumors.

A prospective study of the outcome of traumatic Dorsolumbar fractures treated with posterior stabilization by pedicle screw fixation- A case study

Sept 2024

- A study to evaluate outcomes of dorsolumbar fractures treated with posterior pedicle screw fixation.
- Key findings include significant improvement in kyphotic angle, vertebral height, and functional outcomes.
- Concluded that posterior pedicle screw fixation effectively improves alignment, height restoration, and neurological recovery in dorsolumbar fractures.

Certifications

Understanding Clinical Research: Behind the Statistics	Oct 2022
Covid-19 training for Healthcare Workers	July 2021

Test Score

TOEFL-106 Aug 2024